Guide to the Stanford University Objects Collection SC1048
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Objects
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X124. Leaves from a strawberry-rasberry hybrid., circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.18 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X32 cm. Sample leaves of common garden dahlia. (Showing variation within species when under cultivation.), circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.10 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X71. Subj. natural selection; Wild Boar and modern pig. Ink drawing., circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.20 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X79 cm. Lecture; Instinct & Reason; Structure involving simple reflex; spinal cord, etc., circa 1898; ARCH-AM-00-130.19 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91x271 cm. Black ink drawing on Muslin. Century Magazine, 1907. Man examining two long Rooster tails., circa 1907; ARCH-AM-00-130.06 (Box 1)
  - Drawing, Architectural, framed of Memorial Library. frame 65x79cm, image 48x63 cm., ARCH-AM-00-318 (Box 1)
  - Drawing, Architectural, framed of Memorial Library. Signed Samuel Newsome (same as 2000-318). frame 81x69, image 47x59 cm., ARCH-AM-00-319 (Box 1)
  - Drawing, Architectural, framed, of Memorial Library. Signed Samuel Newsome (same as 2000-318). frame 61 x 113, image 44x96 cm., ARCH-AM-00-323 (Box 1)
  - Drawings, Architectural, Tinted. Leland Stanford Jr. Univ. Shepley, Rutan, & Coolidge. frame 119x48, ARCH-AM-00-327 (Box 1)
  - Drums used by the Band - 2 kettle drums and 1 snare drum; one kettle drum has torn drumhead; 6 drum sticks (one is brush-type); canvas case for snare drum, ARCH-AM-2007-020 (Box 1)
    2007-020.1 kettle drum (intact) 2007-020.2 kettle drum (torn head 2007-020.3 snare drum 2007-020.4 case 2007-020.5 sticks
  - Duplicate image of Donald Kennedy's presidential portrait, ARCH-AM-2005-019 (Box 1)
  - El Tigre Club paddle, circa 1934; ARCH-AM-1980-26 (Box 1)
  - Embosser for defunct University Seal, ARCH-AM-2004-005 (Box 1)
  - Embosser for Vina Agency, ARCH-AM-2008-001 (Box 1)
  - Embosser of the Delta Upsilon Alumni Association (see accn 1997-192 for records), ARCH-AM-1997-016 (Box 1)
  - Embosser with Trustees' seal [now defunct as official seal]: "Seal of the Leland Stanford Junior University 1885" in outer circle, image of tree in the center with "Semper Virens", ARCH-AM-2005-013 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered Indian Head used as model for blankets; designed by A. Phimister Proctor for Dr. Tom Williams, ARCH-AM-1978-11 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered mourning scenes by Mary & Nancy Kellogg: in hinged wood box (includes typed note re. people represented), circa 1840; ARCH-AM-1995-10 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered patch, SU seal (tree, Leland Stanford Junior University, organized 1891)., ARCH-AM-1980-13 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered satin bag (once contained Jane L. Stanford's opera glasses), ARCH-AM-00-027 (Box 1)
  - Enameled Pin: NCAA Women's Final Four San Antonio 2002, ARCH-AM-2008-012 (Box 1)
  - Engraving of L. Stanford portrait with his signature, for printing purposes [used as frontispiece in George T. Clark's biography of LS]. Mounted on red velvet and framed, ARCH-AM-00-043 (Box 1)
  - Ephemera from men's final 4: pins, signs, pennant, cups., ARCH-AM-1998-017 (Box 1)
    98-017.1 pin "FINAL FOUR" with emblems of 4 schools 98-017.2 pin "1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR STANFORD UTAH KENTUCKY NORTH CAROLINA" 98-017.3 pennant: Stanford 1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR 98-017.4 and .5 plastic cup "1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR ALAMODOME" 98-017.6 and .7 plastic cup "1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR SAN ANTONIO" 98-017.8 and .9 two-sided sign: JUST DO IT CARDINAL; JUST DO IT STANFORD
  - Etching, framed, glass, Abeside, Memorial Church. frame 46x34 cm, image 19x14 cm. [MOVED TO PRINT COLLECTION 2/2006], ARCH-AM-00-273 (Box 1)
  - Etching; framed, glass, Title page of eight etchings by Louis Orr. frame 46x34 cm, image 19x14 cm. [MOVED TO PRINT COLLECTION 2/2006], ARCH-AM-00-272 (Box 1)
  - Etching; framed, glass; Old Union and Fountain, signed Louis Orr. frame 47x35 cm, image 21x17 cm., ARCH-AM-00-301 (Box 1)
  - Examples of stone work from the old Encina Gym (razed in 2004): cap stone, 2 squares, example of cast stone, ARCH-AM-2004-010 (Box 1)
  - Fallfest: two red caps, one button (white and blue), 1983; ARCH-AM-1984-12 (Box 1)
  - Fan (Palo Alto tree on red background) from 1999 Convocation, with text of "Hail, Stanford, Hail" and program (2), ARCH-AM-1999-025 (Box 1)
  - Fan from 110th Opening Convocation with program and text of "Hail, Stanford, Hail" on one side and image on the other (5 items), ARCH-AM-00-011 (Box 1)
  - Fan from 117th Convocation; on reverse: program order, text of Hail, Stanford, Hail. (2 items - round paper on wooden handle), ARCH-AM-2008-008 (Box 1)
  - Fan from 124th Convocation; on reverse: program order, text of Hail, Stanford, Hail. (round paper on wooden handle), 2014; ARCH-AM-2016-007 (Box 1)
  - Felt applique in shape of an Indian head with embroidery, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-019 (Box 1)
  - Felt banners: 1) Palo Alto Military Academy, 2) Rose Bowl - Stanford, 3) Stanford (with Indian head), ARCH-AM-1991-095 (Box 1)
  - Felt hat: red & white reversible with diamond shape applique on top, ARCH-AM-1991-092 (Box 1)
  - Felt pennant "Stanford" with tree over the "S" - red letters on white felt., ARCH-AM-1995-34 (Box 1)
  - Fencing Jacke; 79X41cm. White padded shoulders, laces up the front., ARCH-AM-00-131 (Box 1)
  - Fencing jacket of R H. Hull and straw sombrero (reputed to be a senior sombrero from SU class earlier than 1928), ARCH-AM-2006-007 (Box 1)
    2006-007.1 jacket "SU" in red felt on left sleeve 2006-007.2 hat, dark brown woven straw, 19" in diameter
  - Fencing vest used by student in 1895/6, ARCH-AM-00-032 (Box 1)
    see also ACCN 2000-297 for photo of student and fencing master
  - Figure of football and football shoe with plaque "GERHARD CASPER 2000 Rose Bowl Kickoff Luncheon", ARCH-AM-2000-019 (Box 1)
  - Figure of gold miner on base with plaque "In Honor of PRESIDENT G. CASPER GUEST SPEAKER Stanford Sacramento Club 30 March 1993", ARCH-AM-2000-018 (Box 1)
  - Fire place bellows with many initials & names, inc. Bruce Bliven, classes '14, '16, '17. 56x24x5 cm., ARCH-AM-00-266 (Box 1)
  - First academic robe of President Hennessy, ARCH-AM-2003-002 (Box 1)
  - "Beat Cal" buttons (5), 1978-1981; ARCH-AM-1993-04 (Box 1)
  - Flag: French tri-color; possibly used by Stanford ambulance corps during World War I, ARCH-AM-00-064 (Box 1)
  - Flag (US) and Stanford University Board of Trustees banner flown aboard the Space Shuttle Atlantis, STS-110; banner and certificate of authenticity, 2002 Apr 8-19; Accession ARCH-2012-081 (Box 1)
    From the National Aeronautics and Space Administrationand the crew of Atlantis, STS-110.
  - Football autographed by Glenn Warner & Team, ARCH-AM-1978-03 (Box 1)
  - Football banner. Red cowhide; canvas glued on leather with painting of Stanford coed and football player. Irregular shape, approx. 3 x 3 ft., circa 1895; ARCH-AM-1977-09 (Box 1)
  - Football bracelet: chains in shape of footballs, dated 1932, 1935, 1937, 1938, 1940 (3), 1941 all re Frankie Albert, ARCH-AM-1991-021 (Box 1)
  - Football charms, each engraved directly, ARCH-AM-1978-13 (Box 1)
    1: 1908 / J.R. Pemberton forward / Intercollegiate Champions 2: 1908 / Pacific Coast Champions / Stanford 6 California 3: 1907 Intercollegiate Champions / J.R. Pemberton forward
  - Football, inflatable, Accession ARCH-2018-014 (Box 1)
    In white lettering: "join team commute club/transportation.stanford.edu/ bicycle bus carpool train vanpool walk"
  - Football pin: Stanford "S" lapel pin, with small football suspended below., ARCH-AM-1980-21 (Box 1)
  - Football Referee's yellow flag (for calling penalties). NOT one used in any Big Game., ARCH-AM-00-028 (Box 1)
  - Football socks; red wool., circa 1897; ARCH-AM-1981-05 (Box 1)
    An addition to AM 79-12
  - Football sweater, athletic, heavy red wool, knit, long sleeve, turtle neck. 73 x 47 cm., ARCH-AM-1984-42 (Box 1)
  - Football uniform, worn by Darwin B. Lyon Jr., circa 1896; ARCH-AM-1978-07 (Box 1)
  - Football, Big Game, circa 1892; ARCH-AM-1984-45 (Box 1)
  - Football, reputed to be from first big game, ARCH-AM-1978-06 (Box 1)
  - Football: no laces, ARCH-AM-1994-07 (Box 1)
  - Form Board. Psychological Apparatus, 1930. 34x46 cm., ARCH-AM-00-107.2 (Box 1)
  - Founders' Day button: "Celebrate Stanford! Founders' Day April 9, 2000" with image of all 3 Stanfords in center, ARCH-AM-2000-003 (Box 1)
  - Frame from portrait of Homer Laughlin, class of 1896:; Leather, tooled design, padded. [for photo see GP 15693], ARCH-AM-1995-19 (Box 1)
  - Framed collage of women's basketball team 1896, ARCH-AM-1982-13 (Box 1)
  - Framed Letter Envelope: 22x28 & glass. To Mother's Club of Stanford; from Subversive Activities Commitee, 1956., ARCH-AM-00-250 (Box 1)
  - Framed photo (1903) of the chancel in Memorial Church, showing 5 of the statues of the saints, ARCH-AM-2001-08 (Box 1)
  - Framed Photo of Jane Stanford & Leland, Jr. Sepia in gold frame 988x61 cm). Jane faces left., ARCH-AM-00-261 (Box 1)
  - Framed photo of the Stanford Faculty. panoramic view taken in inner quad. this is a duplicate, Winter quarter, 1914; ARCH-AM-00-010 (Box 1)
  - Framed photo of view of campus over Lake Lagunita, pre-1906; ARCH-AM-2001-09 (Box 1)
  - Framed photo reproduction of bird's eye view of Ayrshire Farm, residence of Peter Coutts [same as print 179] Frame OD 38x46cm, image 14x21cm., ARCH-AM-00-361 (Box 1)
  - Framed photo, Breakers Club Stanford Fall 1910. BW Photo. Has some info pasted over glass regarding members. [duplicate of GP2806], ARCH-AM-00-360 (Box 1)
  - Framed photo, BW, Stanford Stock Farm, view of barns. frame OD 28x36cm, image 27x34cm. - DUPLICATE OF GP OS 12726., ARCH-AM-00-362 (Box 1)
  - Framed photo, Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, 5 color photos of SLAC-- exterior and interior. Description on reverse. frame 39x33cm. photos= 5(8x11cm color photos)., ARCH-AM-00-363 (Box 1)
  - Framed photograph of El Palo Alto, circa 1900; ARCH-AM-2002-19 (Box 1)
    Typed inscription reads:My Dad and Mother came to Stanford in 1897, just after their marriage, my father having been hired by David Starr Jordan, President of Stanford. This photo of the beautiful old Palo Alto Tree, circa 1900, was always proudly displayed in our home. This tree rested by the railroad bridge on the north end of Palo Alto.
  - Framed photograph of view of campus over Lake Lagunita, ca. 1905. Gymnasium completed, library not completed., ARCH-AM-2001-17 (Box 1)
  - Framed photograph of William F. Durand, ARCH-AM-1993-06 (Box 1)
  - Framed photos of Nora Stanford Wells and her husband Mr. Wells. Frames were once hinged together, but hinges are now broken, ARCH-AM-2006-008 (Box 1)
  - Framed photos, color and BW, ARCH-AM-00-365 (Box 1)
    1. William J. Bonsall, 1934, BW. frame 41x21cm, image 5x9 2. Mr. and Mrs. Samuel Bonsall, color. frame 41x21cm, image 11x8cm. 3. Text re Memorial fund for 3 professorships and library.
  - Framed Piece of Paper. Glass. "Dr. J.C. Branner to H.C. Hoover, Nove. 30 1893- for services during Month of November, $9.80 et." 13 x 26 cm., ARCH-AM-00-265 (Box 1)
  - Framed Portrait: Judge Samuel F. Lieb, oil painting, in gold frame., ARCH-AM-00-259 (Box 1)
  - Framed prints (large, ornate frames) of Brian Lamprell's color sketches of Stanford views 1998, ARCH-AM-2005-022 (Box 1)
    2005-022.1 Memorial Church 2005-022.2 Main Quad [really inner quad] 2005-022.3 Palm Drive 2005-022.4 Green Library [West Wing front view]
  - Framed reproduction of artist's rendering of Memorial Church (possibly post-quake reconstruction) front oblique view, exterior. frame OD 36x48cm, image 21x38cm., ARCH-AM-00-364 (Box 1)
  - Framed sepia photos of arboretum view, ARCH-AM-1995-24 (Box 1)
  - Framed under glass, 33X25 cm. Stanford Daily headlines, 1938-40 collage style., ARCH-AM-00-178 (Box 1)
  - Framed- Stanford Coeds. Series of Individual Portraits., circa 1895; ARCH-AM-00-357 (Box 1)
  - Free standing photo frame, possibly brass, ornate trim., ARCH-AM-1992-08 (Box 1)
  - French "Croix de Guerre" from flag pole (US flag used by Stanford Ambulance Corps??), ARCH-AM-00-065.1 (Box 1)
  - French horn #12393 in case "Property of Stanford University Bands", ARCH-AM-1999-018 (Box 1)
  - Freshman "dink" (cap), 1917; ARCH-AM-1993-08 (Box 1)
  - Frisbee: "Sequoia Travel Center, Tresidder Union" red & white, ARCH-AM-1985-008 (Box 1)
  - Glass jar with label: "Varian 50th Anniversary Blackberry Jam", ARCH-AM-1999-003 (Box 1)
  - Glasses, "Nerd Nation", ARCH-AM-2017-013 (Box 1)
  - Gold key presented to Mrs. Lucie Stern by SU in appreciation for her gift of Ruth Lucie Stern Research Lab, 1939, St. Med., ARCH-AM-1977-02 (Box 1)
  - Gold pocket watch (1919) and wedding ring of Chester Naramore, with suede leather pouch, 1919 and undated; ARCH-AM-2009-026 (Box 1)
    2009-026.1 Watch is engraved inside: "Chet" in appreciation from Petroleum Division U.S.B.M. Feb. 1st 1919; outside has initials entwined CN 2009-026.2 Ring is engraved: G.E.C. to C. N. 2009-026.3 Suede pouch
  - Graduation tassel, Class of 2002, ARCH-AM-2010-005 (Box 1)
  - Greek marble piece from fireplace mantel, incised with "S", ARCH-AM-2005-031 (Box 1)
  - Green armband issued to faculty observers to be used during campus disturbances, 1971; ARCH-AM-2010-015 (Box 1)
  - Green Teas Stanford Libraries 2008-2009, coffee cup (white with black interior), ARCH-AM-2009-021 (Box 1)
  - Gym Suit: black bloomers, white shirt, black sash, black vest, circa 1900; ARCH-AM-1983-05 (Box 1)
  - Hard hat - white with Stanford seal on front; used during Library basement remodeling, ARCH-AM-1979-16 (Box 1)
  - Hard hat - white with Stanford seal on front; used during Library basement remodeling, ARCH-AM-1979-17 (Box 1)
  - Hard hat (1) White, on front: "The Leland Stanford Mansion;" on back: "Team Stanford Mansion." Baseball Cap (1) Red, on front: "Stanford Football" (with "S" Logo)., undated; ARCH-AM-2009-033 (Box 1)
    2009-033.1 White hard hat 2009-033.2 Red baseball cap
  - Hat (beanie style) and red tie with L'Il Injun design painted on it, ca. 1951, ARCH-AM-2006-001 (Box 1)
    2006-001.1 Hat 2006-001.2 Tie
  - Hat, writing on brim, red, "Stanford, Stanford, Hurrah, Hurro" '12., 1912; ARCH-AM-1984-25 (Box 1)
  - Hat, signed on brim by members of the classes of 1914-1918, circa 1918; ARCH-AM-2011-003 (Box 1)
  - Hat, beanie, 9x21, gray with red button, size 6 7/8, ARCH-AM-1984-28 (Box 1)
  - Hat, Plug Ugly, of R.S. Lewis, 1905; ARCH-AM-00-106 (Box 1)
  - Hat, red and white, '12, 28x21x13cm., ARCH-AM-1984-27 (Box 1)
  - Hat, red felt with thin white band. 28 x 25cm., ARCH-AM-1984-46 (Box 1)
  - Hat, Senior Sombrero, Maker = The Regent, Palo Alto. 32x99x11 cm., ARCH-AM-1984-26 (Box 1)
  - Hat, Sombero, signatures of '08, '09, '03. "R. L. Holman on brim., circa 1908; ARCH-AM-00-268 (Box 1)
  - Hats - sombrero and plug ugly, ARCH-AM-1997-012 (Box 1)
    1. Senior Sombrero - leather band with "Stanford 11"; S.B.S. on inner band 2. Plug Ugly, S.B.S. class of 1911 - paintings: Encina Club, History, woman's face, 1911 banner
  - Hats and beanies, ARCH-AM-1983-07 (Box 1)
    0. freshman beanie, gray 1. felt hat, red, with gray band 2. felt hat, red; 3. leather belt, brown, with buckle, "Stanford" 4. leather hat band for a senior "Sombrero" 5. ribbon, red and blue, with small buckle
  - Hats: 1 sophomore dink, 1 baseball hat (red felt), ARCH-AM-1981-07 (Box 1)
  - Herbert Hoover Medal for Distinguished Service presented to J. Wallace Sterling by Stanford Alumni Association with case, 1964; ARCH-AM-2009-012 (Box 1)
  - Herbert Hoover Medal for Distinguished Service, Stanford Alumni Association ["blank" - not awarded to anyone], pre-1985; ARCH-AM-2009-013 (Box 1)
  - High heeled shoes originally with Carol Green's scrapbook, ARCH-AM-1996-01 (Box 1)
  - High School Musical 3 doll: Off to College Gabriella (in Stanford outfit), 2008; ARCH-AM-2009-042 (Box 1)
    Copy 1 is missing the "Disney" sticker on upper left of original box. Copy 2 [added March 2010] is complete.
  - homemade tag, small banner for 75th anniversay (2000), an award plaque from Children's Wish Foundation International (includes photo of APO member with a child at a playground), Golden Anniversary seal, hand puppet in shape of a beaver, and Playskool Cobbler's Bench labeled "APO Female Presidents' Gavel", ARCH-AM-2007-013 (Box 1)
    2007-013.1 tag 2007-013.2 small banner 2007-013.3 plaque 2007-013.4 Golden anniversary seal 2007-013.5 beaver puppet 2007-013.6 "Female Presidents' Gavel."
  - Honor the Game - button and brochure re program sponsored by Positive Coaching Alliance, ARCH-AM-2002-17 (Box 1)
  - Hoover House construction materials, 2001: Original roofing tile and sample of new replacement tile, ARCH-AM-2002-04 (Box 1)
  - Horn, used at Big Game March., 1892; ARCH-AM-00-033 (Box 1)
    22 inches, tin; barely readable on shaft of horn is "Ball Game L.S.J. U. [v?] UC March 19, 1892" and the name Harriett J. Fyffe. On the fluted edge is "Rah, Rah, Rah / Rah, Rah" and the name Minnie B. Yoder
  - Horn, used at Stanford-Nebraska Rose Bowl game, 1941; by Roos Bros.; red/white, ARCH-AM-00-034 (Box 1)
  - Horseshoe, ARCH-AM-1992-010 (Box 1)
  - Indian doll with bendable arms and legs, originally owned by Walt Peterson, ARCH-AM-1997-011 (Box 1)
  - Insulated coffee cup with lid "Stanford Bookstore Cafe & Confections", circa 1995; ARCH-AM-2007-030 (Box 1)
  - Insulated cup, Stanford University, Arts Intensive Program, 2013; ARCH-AM-2014-004 (Box 1)
  - Insulated cup, Stanford University, Bing Honors College, 2013; ARCH-AM-2014-003 (Box 1)
  - Insulated cup, Stanford University, Sophomore College, 2013; ARCH-AM-2014-002 (Box 1)
  - Invitation to party for Sandy Riser - inside a paper cup with plastic stick, ARCH-AM-1993-14 (Box 1)
  - Ivory handled razor, "Francis B. Loomis" on handle., ARCH-AM-00-151.1 (Box 1)
  - Ivory handled razor., ARCH-AM-00-151.2 (Box 1)
  - J. L. Stanford portrait mask, ARCH-AM-00-068.5 (Box 1)
  - Jacket, reversible red/khaki, with round patch "STANFORD BAND" around Indian head, ARCH-AM-2002-22 (Box 1)
  - Japanese Caligraphy in black frame with glass-110x65 cm., ARCH-AM-00-088 (Box 1)
  - Jewelry- pins, money clip, ARCH-AM-1983-03 (Box 1)
    1. Pin: gold, red enamel, with seal of LSJU (1/2'"" diam.) origin: Donor Estates 2. Phi Beta Kappa Pin: gold on back: ""Zoe Watkins, Stanford, 1910,"" origin: Zoe L. Watkins, 1910 3. FOB: gold, red enamel, with seal of LSJU. Ring attached. On back: "Zoe L. Watkins, Kingman, Arizona" 14k. origin: Zoe L. Watkins 4. Pin: gold, black enamel pin in shape of mortarboard on back: "Zoe Watkins, 1910" 14k. origin: Zoe L. Watkins 5. Money Clip: silver, engraved: "Florence Loomis, Burlingame, California."
  - Jewelry: three small pins, incl. on lsju seal (.5cm diam) and two gold pins, ARCH-AM-1982-12 (Box 1)
  - Key chain; enameled picture (multi-colored) of front of quad from palm drive., ARCH-AM-1980-09 (Box 1)
  - Key, 4 cm long, "Key to trunk at Union Safe Deposit with C.P. Huntington. J.L.S. " labelled, ARCH-AM-00-210 (Box 1)
  - Keychain, facsimile of Big Game 1981 ticket. Bronze colored metal. with ring., ARCH-AM-1982-08 (Box 1)
  - Klystron tubes, ARCH-AM-1996-03 (Box 1)
    - AM 96-03.01--AM 96-03.05 (Box 1)
      AM 96-03.01 Stanford type 410R, 2 cavity oscillator. Designed by E. L. Ginzton and Don Snow; built at San Carlos plant. late 1930s (earliest one in collection); AM 96-03.02 "C" band amplifier, 3 cavity, type VA122a; copy of a Sperry design (SAC45A). Built at Varian, San Carlos; AM 96-03.03 Reflex tube 417C; original Sperry number built by Varian. Used by the Navy; AM 96-03.04 Sperry amplifier, "C" band, 3 cavities. Live tube. Designed for 100 watts output microwave instument landing transmitter; AM 96-03.05 Klystron frequency multiplier from early 1940s; probably built at Sperry San Carlos or at Stanford.
    - AM 96-03.06--AM 96-03.08 (Box 2)
      AM 96-03.06 Production version of #5. Used to drive the instrument landing transmitter and also the local oscillator in the receiver for instrument landing or aviation landing; AM 96-03.07 Experimental amplifier built in San Carlos in early 1950s (A 24G). Built for Ryan Aeronautical Corp. in San Diego for a doppler navigation system. Five cavities, tunable, produced a few watts output at very high gain; AM 96-03.08 Section of one of the earlier Sperry "S" band 3 cavity amplifiers.
    - AM 96-03.09--AM 96-03.10 (Box 3)
      AM 96-03.9 Varian Associates 517; 2 cavity oscillator. Used for the Hawk missile guidance system; AM 96-03.10 Varian type VA912A; 3 cavitgy amplifier operating in "C" band; designed as a second source for the Sperry SAC47
    - AM 96-03.11--AM 96-03.13 (Box 4)
      AM 96-03.11A Varian VA204; reflex klystron oscillator; AM 96-03.11B Reflex oscillator (in two parts; can be disassembled), shows the cathode portion through one window and the reflector through the other; AM 96-03.12 Three cavity amplifier klystron designed for mass production using a clam shell type of structure for the cavities. This structure was electro formed on a mandrel, believed to have been designed and built by Don Snow in San Carlos in the early 1950s; AM 96-03.13 Sperry-type 2K34 type klystron. Two cavity oscillator with a third cavity acting as a buffer to isolate the oscillator section from load variations.
  - Knobby Adaline - weather prediction machine buildt by Bernard Widrow; used in San Francisco, ca. 1960, ARCH-AM-1997-020 (Box 1)
  - Konrad B. Krauskopt medals with cases, 1960 and undated; ARCH-AM-2009-011 (Box 1)
    2009-011.1 Gold medal awarded by The Geological Society of American, 1960 2009-011.2 Gold medal awarded by The Geochemical Society, undated
  - L'il Injun decal, circa 1950; ARCH-AM-2009-003 (Box 1)
  - L'il Injun watch, ARCH-AM-1982-02 (Box 1)
  - L'il Injun window sticker, ARCH-AM-1982-03 (Box 1)
  - Label button "Happy Birthday Donald Tresidder", Apr. 6, 1979; ARCH-AM-1979-11 (Box 1)
  - label pin: "Stanford Basketball 1998-99 Season Celebrating 25 Years", ARCH-AM-1999-008 (Box 1)
  - Label: 5.5x7 cm, Color, Palo Alto Brand of Tomatoes., ARCH-AM-00-202 (Box 1)
  - Labels, "Bookmaker's Ale," specially bottled beer from the Anchor Brewing Co. served at SUL-sponsored reception at ALA meeting in San Francisco, 1997 June 27; ARCH-AM-1998-012 (Box 1)
  - Labels, "Bookmaker's Ale," specially bottled beer from the Anchor Brewing Co. served at SUL-sponsored reception at ALA meeting in San Francisco (2), 1997 June 27; Accession ARCH-AM-2018-011 (Box 1)
  - Lace bedspread (or possibly tablecloth) used by Hopkins [Lydia] 1873 and on, with two smaller cloths of same design., ARCH-AM-1989-188 (Box 1)
  - Ladies Pins., ARCH-AM-00-211 (Box 1)
    00-211.1 Ladies Stick Pin, with Lacey gold design. 2.5x3x5 cm. 00-211.2 Ladies Stick Pin, with Lacey gold design. 2.5x3x5 cm.
  - Lantern Slide Projector (old) for 3" to 4" slides, ARCH-AM-00-254 (Box 1)
  - Large bolt (2 of them) distributed as keepsakes at ground breaking ceremony for Cantor Center; third one came with accn 2008-107, ARCH-AM-1995-27 (Box 1)
  - large poster: duplication of framed axe, ARCH-AM-2002-14 (Box 1)
  - Large red felt rectangle with "STANFORD' in white letters; white satin along left edge with red/white streamers at three points., ARCH-AM-2001-05 (Box 1)
  - Large scale replica of "Think Again" cube (8 inch), undated; ARCH-AM-2009-036 (Box 1)
  - Laundry bag from Stanford Laundry of Palo Alto "Where Device & Care Prolong Wear", ARCH-AM-2001-36 (Box 1)
  - Leaded glass window from Hoover House front door (plain glass)., ARCH-AM-2002-10 (Box 1)
  - Leather hat band: "Stanford 24", ARCH-AM-1999-014 (Box 1)
  - Leather piece from Stanford Harness - black leather with brass "S" on both sides, ARCH-AM-1995-31 (Box 1)
  - Leather postcards (2): "Rah Rah Rah, Stanford", ARCH-AM-00-061 (Box 1)